LIAM MCGOVERN

STUDENT

Motivated individual with strong work ethic and ability to work both independently and as part of a team. Reliable, hardworking and conscientious. Dedicated to working until deadlines are completed and always meeting highest standards. Possessing a sharp analytical mindset and expertise in data analytics. Throughout my final year at university, I thoroughly enjoyed the challenges of analysing data, showcasing a strong commitment to precision and the ability to uncover valuable insights. I am enthusiastic about continuing to develop in this area and expanding my skill set further. I believe I am suited for an analyst/technology role.

Contact

Phone

087-1759882

Email

liam.mcgovern23@mail.dcu.ie

Address

9 St. Brigid's Green, Artane, Dublin D05X4E3

Education

2021 - Present

Business Studies with Data Analytics Dublin City University

2014 - 2021

Leaving Cerificate - 532 points Ardscoil Rís Dublin

Technical Skills

- Python
- SOL
- Power BI
- Tableau
- Microsoft Word (Expert)
- Microsoft Excel (Associate)
- Microsoft PowerPoint

Soft skills

- Time Management
- Collaborative/Leadership
- Oral/written communication
- Proactive
- Analytical

Experience

Fraud Analyst

Bank of Ireland | 40 Mespil Road D04 C2N4

06/2022 - PRESENT

- Compile detailed fraud reports for the investigation department for fraudulent transaction that occur
- Verify inbound callers, transfer to another department if required
- Cancel and reissued any cards lost, stolen, or compromised
- Delete any digital tokens that are needed to be
- Ensure devices and online banking 365 is secure
- Lift any blocks caused by suspicious transactions if confirmed by a verified cardholder.
- · Continuously engage with customers and management within the department to ensure all's needs are met with excellence and due diligence.

General Floor Operator

The Paddy Box | Ballymun Enterprise Centre, D11 CVY6 10/2021 - 12/2021

- Insured products ordered were correct and matched invoices received
- Prepared boxes to allow other staff to carry out order packaging
- Condensed all boxes onto pallets to be collected for delivery
- · Consulted with manager with regards to the amount of stock present and what goods needed to be ordered
- · Organized raw materials received to maximize space and accessibility to these materials for other staff.

Customer Advisor

Bank of Ireland | IFSC Branch 01/2021 - 09/2021

- · Provided a highly professional and friendly service to both business and personal customers and maintained a constant visible presence on the floor
- I strived to solve any customer queries swiftly and efficiently, and if I was unsure, I consulted with another member of the branch team.
- Encouraged customers to switch to online banking and happily answered any questions they had in relation to this.
- · Carried out daily tasks such as approving cheques, printing and signing reports, running dockets, opening accounts, and executing Interpays for customers.
- Insured that ATMs were continuously operation and balanced them at the end of each

Reference

Gerard Flynn

Fraud Security Manager | Bank Of Ireland Director E2E | Bank Of Ireland

Phone: 086 - 050 2237 Email: ger.flynn@boi.com

Sean L'Estrange

Phone: 087 - 1160250

Email: sean.l'estrange@boi.com

Education

Dublin City University

09/2021 - Expected 05//2024

BBA: Business Studies specialising in Data Analytics

Having engaged with a wide array of modules, I've acquired skills in multiple domains:

- Entrepreneurship
- Agile and digital thinking
- Operations management
- Fund accounting
- Expertise in data analytics with a focus on leveraging tools such as Python, SQL, and Power BI.

Ardscoil Rís

2014 - 2020

Leaving Certificate - 532 Points

Business	H1
Maths	Н2
Geography	Н2
Chemistry	НЗ
Accounting	НЗ
English	НЗ
Irish	НЗ

Languages

English & Irish

Interests / Hobbies

GAA (St. Vincents GAA Club)

Golf (Clontarf Golf Club)

Gym (Westwood Gyms)

Sea swimming (High Rock Malahide/ Dollymount)

Socialising with friends (Work/Sport/College/School)